[The Unclouded Soul]
[Episode 29]
Support Admin Watch on
kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
Elders, you have to believe me.
This is exactly what Hong Ye is like.
My Lord has returned.
My Lord, who has been working tirelessly
for the demons,
has finally returned.
This time,
what sacred demon relic have you
brought back for us?
I don't need to report my whereabouts
to you.
I'm asking on behalf of the elders.
Rumors say
you've been quite close with humans.
You don't even care
about demons being humiliated anymore.
Where did these rumors come from?
Whatever one does
always leaves traces.
Well said.
Everything done leaves a trace behind.
As the Demon Lord,
I should indeed thoroughly investigate
the rumors about you.
Since you claim
you're asking on behalf of the elders,
then let the elders
share their concerns
directly with me.
Hong Ye,
we made you our Demon King
to revitalize our demon kind
and to resist human aggression.
Don't lose your way.
Heiwu has been working tirelessly
to strengthen our demon forces.
But you,
every time you go to the human realm
seeking sacred demon relics,
you face all sorts of difficulties.
Since you're here today,
you should first clarify
your relationship with the humans.
Otherwise,
if these rumors are proven true,
we old fellows
can no longer take your side.
Elders,
the grievances between our two races
have existed for ages.
But if demons truly want to find peace,
we must understand how humans think.
His Lordship is so powerful.
How many years has he been cultivating?
At least a thousand years.
Four thousand years?
Five or six thousand years?
Anyway,
it's not more than ten thousand years.
I've never seen
a demon who lived over ten thousand years.
So you don't know either.
What...
are you talking about?
Let me tell you,
in the entire Demons' Valley,
there's nothing about His Lordship
that I don't know.
Ask me anything.
All right, all right.
Then tell me what
His Lordship's true form is.
His Lordship's true form is...
His...
His Lordship's...
What's His Lordship's true form again?
Why are you sighing?
It's not that I don't know.
It's that, for this kind of thing,
if His Lordship
doesn't mention it himself,
it's not something we can ask about.
But there's one thing
I can guarantee
is absolutely true.
What?
That His Lordship's power
used to be extremely weak—
incredibly weak.
But the previous Demon King
admired His Lordship greatly.
He said His Lordship
was the most talented individual
with the greatest potential
in the entire demon race.
So before the old Demon King passed away,
he left instructions
specifically naming His Lordship
as the new Demon King
to protect the entire demon race.
But because His Lordship's power
was truly too weak,
many great demons were not convinced.
They said His Lordship was
unworthy of the position.
So to prove himself, His Lordship
broke and rebuilt
all the meridians in his body—
he was at death's door.
That's what made him
the strongest and most powerful
great demon of our time.
And as for His Lordship's identity,
there are many theories
throughout the demon race.
Do you know
what the most ridiculous one is?
Some demons say
that His Lordship
sprang from some crack in a rock.
How could that be possible?
And others say
that His Lordship is a descendant
of the long-extinct ancient dragon clan.
Actually, I think
His Lordship himself isn't clear
about what his true identity is.
But it doesn't matter.
No matter who he is
or where he came from,
it doesn't change the fact that
he is now the most powerful demon
of our time.
That's enough.
He never mentioned any of this to me.
That's normal.
He has always been a man of few words.
You'll get used to it eventually.
But do you know
what I've seen him do most often
is?
He'd just stand here,
looking over there,
at the moon,
as if waiting for something,
with a lonely expression.
It always made my heart ache.
Perhaps it's just as the old saying goes:
the more powerful one's power is,
the more one has to sacrifice,
and the lonelier one feels.
Have you ever seen him cry?
Are you kidding?
Why would the Demon King ever cry?
I'm serious.
I'm serious too!
So what if he's the Demon King?
Not even once?
Actually, I think
even if he does cry,
he'd find a place where no one can see him
and cry in secret.
After all,
he is the Demon King.
So,
since then,
Xiao Mu and I decided
we would stick with him,
keep him company,
stay by his side,
and talk to him constantly—
even if it's nonsense,
we'd keep talking to him.
Maybe in that moment
he would feel less alone.
After talking with you today,
I want to be even better to him!
-I want to be—
-You're already good enough to him.
Not at all!
More than enough.
Is His Lordship coming back soon?
Should we go welcome him?
Oh right, I completely forgot about that,
chatting with you all this time.
I'm afraid you'll talk
His Lordship to death.
Humans,
out of fear of demons,
slaughter demons.
Demons, hating humans,
eat humans.
It's a vicious cycle—
difficult to break.
The best solution now
is for both races
to cease fighting
and coexist peacefully.
His Lordship always comes and goes alone,
but he's different only with you.
Not only does he protect you,
he also smiles at you often.
In that brief moment just now—
I counted—
he smiled at you four times.
That's more than he's smiled
at me in the entire year.
Tell me honestly.
Who are you really?
Perhaps because I'm new here,
His Lordship is just looking after me.
Let me tell you,
in Demons' Valley,
the most important person
to listen to is His Lordship.
After that,
it's Xiao Mu
and me.
You...
Where are you going?
Go that way.
Where does this path lead to?
It leads to the prison.
Nothing worth seeing there.
Prison?
The Demons' Valley a hundred years later
doesn't have a place like this.
Who do they keep in there?
Seriously?
Human prisons hold demons;
naturally, demon prisons hold humans.
What are they captured for?
What do you think
we do to them?
Have you ever eaten a human?
No.
I heard human flesh isn't tasty.
It's dry and tough,
nowhere near as good as dried fish.
Who would eat humans?
Humans are reserved
for the great demons and elders—
never for somebody like me.
What are you doing?
I told you there's nothing to see.
Help!
Save me!
-Help!
-Save me!
Help!
Help me!
Save me!
-Help!
-Save me!
-Save me.
-You can't eat this.
They are for the sacrifice.
Please save me!
I beg you—
I beg you, immortal demon lord,
-please spare my life.
-Stop shouting.
My Lord,
I'm just
a city guard from the human realm.
I know my mistake
of accidentally disturbing
your meditation.
I beg you, My Lord,
spare me.
I have a family to support!
Let me tell you,
no human who enters Demons' Valley
leaves alive.
I swear to heaven!
I will never reveal anything
about what happened in this valley.
If you don't believe me, My Lord,
I am willing
to gouge out my eyes
and bite off my tongue.
-Save me!
-I beg you, My Lord,
spare my life.
Enough.
Stop your senseless crying.
That's enough.
You've seen enough.
We need to go welcome His Lordship.
Let's go.
Princess.
Stop looking.
Let's hurry.
His Lordship, don't leave!
Don't go, His Lordship!
Those children are only 6 or 7 years old.
Why won't they spare
even such young children?
Humans may have short lives,
but they grow up fast.
In just over 10 years,
they can reach adulthood.
Unlike us demons,
who need at least
several hundred years of cultivation
just to barely transform into human form.
Do you know how much
it took for Xiao Mu and me
to take this human form?
Hong Ye
hasn't eaten humans before, right?
What?
Hong Ye.
How dare you!
How dare you address
His Lordship by his name?
Has he or has he not?
I don't know.
Though I haven't seen it myself,
but think about it:
His Lordship has been in this world
for thousands of years.
What hasn't he seen?
What hasn't he eaten?
Eating a human
is nothing strange.
You go ahead first.
I'll come along later.
Where are you going?
His Lordship told me
to keep a close eye on you.
to take good care of you.
I need to relieve myself now.
You staying right here
and waiting for me to return
would be the best care you could provide.
Don't follow me.
I don't even want to follow you.
Hurry up.
Elders, look at this.
This is our Demon King,
a king who sympathizes with humans
and speaks for humans at every turn.
Do you think
he still deserves
to sit on the Demon King's throne?
The survival of our demon race
is a long-term strategy,
not something as shortsighted
as you perceive it.
I'm shortsighted?
Me?
Only absolute suppression
can bring true peace!
Hmm.
Our demon race
has suffered humiliation from humans
for thousands of years.
As the Demon King,
instead of thinking about revenge,
you stand with the humans.
Elders, look at this.
Hong Ye's words today
aren't thoughts formed in just a few days.
He must have
harbored treacherous intentions
for a long time.
Hong Ye,
trusting human nature
will lead to irreversible disaster.
Hong Ye,
do you know
your getting too close
to the humans
was told to us by a human?
Wu Huan!
Bring them here!
-Sister, please help me.
-Please save me.
Don't speak.
I will take you out of here.
Hurry.
Follow me.
Hold hands.
Princess,
please spare my life too.
Earlier in the palace,
I've offended you many times,
but that was just my duty.
I never meant to offend you, Princess.
You've already hit me too.
I only beg you, Princess,
to spare my life.
I promise
to take these three children
safely back home.
About what happened in this valley,
I won't say a word.
I will forever be grateful for your
great kindness and mercy.
Please give me a chance
to redeem myself.
You liar.
You're helping humans?
Princess,
let me go!
I'll protect you from this cat demon.
You're
a human princess?
Yes.
I am a human princess,
but I'm also Hong Ye's friend.
You've been deceiving His Lordship!
I haven't deceived anyone.
Hong Ye has great powers.
How could I possibly deceive him?
He brought me here
so that humans and demons
could understand each other better.
He's seeking
a way for coexistence.
You're talking nonsense!
How is that possible?
Why not?
Must we fight
and kill each other every day?
The princess is right.
Humans and demons coexisting
is the right way!
Shut up.
If you don't believe me,
you can ask Hong Ye.
I...
I can't just take your word for it.
If you want to free the humans,
it must be His Lordship
who says so in person.
Oh no.
Wu Huan is coming.
He must be here for the sacrifices.
Princess.
Save me, Princess!
Quick!
Please save me, Princess!
Save me, Princess, please!
Help me!
Quick,
take them to those bushes over there
and hide them.
I'll deal with him.
Go now!
Let's go.
Come on, move!
Ning'an.
I've never seen His Lordship
as happy as today.
Remember,
don't disappoint His Lordship.
Go!
Where are the humans?
I ate them.
Three small ones and one big one—
you ate them all?
Yes.
Those three small ones were quite tender,
but the big one wasn't good.
He's too tough,
and fatty.
Do you know who they were?
The big one was the Feiyu Guard leader.
We needed him alive for questioning.
Those three small ones were sacrifices
for the ancestral ceremony
on the first day.
And you just ate them?
Look.
You're getting upset.
You didn't put up any signs here.
How was I supposed to know?
Don't you usually only eat
rotten fish, prawns,
grasshoppers, and rats?
Since when did you start eating humans?
Don't mention it.
The weather's been bad these days.
My dried fish isn't ready yet.
I was starving,
so I had to eat them.
Fine.
Since you admit you ate them,
come back with me to Youning Cave
to explain to the elders.
Take your claws off me.
You ate them?
The human Feiyu Guard
I worked so hard to capture
admitted himself
that Demon King is secretly colluding
with the human royal family.
I came to confront the Demon King
with this person,
and the next thing I know,
you've eaten him?
I believe it.
But do the elders believe it?
Why did you eat the humans?
I was hungry.
You were hungry?
The elders are hungry too.
What he ate were sacrifices.
This is a serious crime.
He should be punished.
You did that too?
Yes.
I wasn't satisfied with just one,
so I ate all three of them.
You ate them all in such a short time?
Weren't there other demons
sharing with you?
Why should I share with other demons?
Well.
Very well.
Given what you said,
stealing offerings
deserves
the punishment of lightning.
Fine.
Xiao Ming caused trouble
because I didn't discipline him properly.
I'll take the punishment for him.
No, no!
Silence!
Even if the cat stole the offerings,
we're punishing him
because he overstepped his bounds.
How could we punish
the Demon King instead?
But what if
the Demon King ordered his subordinate
to silence others,
who should be punished then?
Without solid evidence,
we
should not make baseless accusations.
Recently,
the human Feiyu Guard
has repeatedly invaded Demons' Valley,
and many demons
have suffered at their hands.
Hong Ye,
as the Demon King,
you've failed to protect the residents
of Demons' Valley,
yet you constantly speak
in favor of humans.
That human has been captured by me
for days,
as all the elders know.
This cat
normally eats fish and mice,
but today he swallowed
so many living humans.
Tell me,
without orders from you, his master,
would he dare to do such a thing?
Heiwu.
You needn't go to such lengths
to fabricate crimes against me.
Today I'll fulfill your wish.
If punishment is required,
I accept it.
Good.
The cat is Hong Ye's trusted aide.
Whether it's poor supervision
or secret instructions,
stealing offerings
makes his punishment justified.
Elders,
please
cast the lightning spell for punishment.
Come.
Swear to heaven.
I, Wang Hong,
swear to heaven
that upon leaving Demons' Valley,
I will definitely
take these three children
safely back to their families.
As everything I've seen and heard
in this valley,
I won't say a word
after leaving this place.
No.
I want you, after you return,
to tell my father everything you've seen
and experienced.
Tell him that demons are like humans,
there are good and bad among them.
Say that I hope Father
can be kind and benevolent
to reconcile and coexist
with the demons.
To reconcile
and coexist
with the demons.
If this oath is broken,
heaven's punishment will surely follow.
Oh, no.
I, Wang Hong,
will definitely keep my oath!
My Lord!
Let me go!
My Lord.
My Lord!
No...
No!
Stop!
This has nothing to do with His Lordship!
I ate the offering!
My Lord!
My Lord.
It's not a big deal.
Why are you crying so much?
I have my power to protect me.
I'm fine.
My Lord,
Heiwu clearly wanted to kill you.
If it had been me instead,
I would have been destroyed completely.
Where is Ning'an?
Where are those humans?
Tell me quickly.
My Lord,
don't trust the human race too much.
They...
Hong Ye.
Ning'an.
Does it hurt?
I'm fine.
You released those humans?
They're just children.
You're lying!
-She let the Feiyu Guard go—
-Shut up.
Just tell me
where they are.
I just want to ask you one thing.
Answer me honestly.
Have you ever eaten humans?
I've fought against humans
for thousands of years,
and indeed many human warriors
and sorcerers
have died by my hand.
But something as tasteless and vile
as eating humans
is something I've never done.
Mm-hmm.
I believe what you say.
Those children and the Feiyu Guard,
I've hidden them at Chenxiang Sea.
Whether to release them or keep them—
I wanted to discuss it with you.
My Lord,
you absolutely cannot let humans
know the secrets of Demons' Valley.
If that happens,
they might plunder our treasures,
and at worst,
countless lives might be lost.
For self-preservation,
demons would have to migrate elsewhere
to survive.
Please think carefully!
Jump down.
Jump.
Demon King,
Your Highness,
I have already sworn an oath.
Please spare my life.
Return to the human realm
and keep your promise.
Children, come here.
Hug your shoulders
like me.
Close your eyes.
Count from 1 to 10 silently,
and then you can open your eyes.
My Lord,
the future of our demon race
now depends entirely on the humans.
It's far too dangerous.
If disaster strikes,
we'll all be beyond redemption.
I must return to the human realm now.
I'll meet with my father.
I'll tell him
that the Demon King
has chosen to trust humans,
to temporarily cease hostilities.
It's now on humans to decide
how we should respond.
Very well.
I'll escort you back.
My Lord.
What if Ning'an
doesn't return after this?
Ning'an will return.
I...
You...
You never listen to anything I say.
I give up!
Seriously!
What if my father detains me
and I can't escape?
Then I'll come rescue you.
What if I
am no longer in this world?
Why are you suddenly asking this?
I just want to know.
What if I
die?
Then I'll find you in your next life.
Hong Ye.
Promise me,
if,
when you find me again,
I have changed,
you and Princess Ning'an
will just be friends.
Just be friends.
Will you promise?
No.
Why not?
Because I love you.
Perhaps it's because of your kindness,
your purity,
and your loyalty.
You showed me
a different kind of human realm.
You also allowed me to see
the future of our two races
I've never envisioned before.
But all of this is because
you
are you.
You've never spoken like this before.
Of course not.
I've never said such things to anyone.
You're the first
and will be the only one.
What if I
weren't Princess Ning'an?
I like you.
No matter what your name is,
what your status is,
whether you're human or spirit,
it doesn't matter.
I just don't know
if you feel the same way.
I do.
Coming back here,
it feels like it'd been forever.
Go back to your palace first
and get some good rest.
Whatever happens,
I'll face it with you.
Then I want you to stay with me
until I fall asleep.
Leave after I'm asleep.
All right.
Don't move.
It's a small trick.
Your Majesty,
Princess Ning'an has returned.
She entered Yong'an Palace
with the Demon King.
She really came back with the Demon King.
It's absolutely true.
They've entered the array set
by the Feiyu Guard.
By now,
they should be fighting already.
[Yong'an Palace]
It's you.
I thank Your Highness for saving my life.
After we kill the Demon King,
I will certainly report to His Majesty
that you led the Demon King into our trap.
You're full of lies!
I told you to tell my father the truth.
What did you say?
I reported truthfully.
I was simply careless
and fell into the trap
of the cunning demons.
Fortunately, the princess saved me
and I escaped with my life.
Therefore,
all the more we should kill the Demon King
to redeem ourselves
and serve the royal family.
Hong Ye suffered lightning punishment
to save you.
How dare you be so ungrateful.
The princess just said
Hong Ye
has just endured lightning punishment
and his power is greatly diminished.
Feiyu Guard, hear my orders!
Whoever wounds Demon King Hong Ye
will be rewarded with gold.
Whoever kills Hong Ye
will be granted a title!
Activate the array!
I was going to let you all go,
but now I really want you dead.
I'm carrying Hong Ye's child.
If you kill him,
you're killing me too.
Feiyu Guards, you've all heard it.
[Yong'an Palace]
The princess is entangled with demons
and blinded by demonic arts.
Now she's carrying a demon spawn.
If the princess is harmed,
it's considered loyalty
in capturing demons.
Who dares to touch her?
Imperial decree!
Everyone stop!
[Yong'an Palace]
All you servants,
kneel down!
Kneel!
His Majesty's verbal decree:
Princess Ning'an and Demon King Hong Ye
are summoned to the palace.
His Majesty also said,
to show his sincerity,
only I will escort
Your Highness and the Demon King
to the royal study.
Step aside now!
[Yong'an Palace]
Your Highness,
Demon King,
this way, please.
Your Highness and Demon King,
please wait here.
Ning'an.
You've finally returned.
Are you...
injured?
Were you frightened just now?
I will punish those Feiyu Guards at once!
I am...
fine, Father.
Thank you for your concern.
Rise, please rise.
That's good.
During these days when you were away,
I worried about you every day.
Meeting for the first time,
I must seem foolish to the Demon King.
Leave now.
Without my permission,
no one is to enter.
The Demon King and I
have important matters to discuss.
You may go.
Yes, Your Majesty.
You may leave.
I have
no spiritual power
and no magical techniques.
If the Demon King wishes to kill me now,
it would be effortless.
If killing me
could bring peace to the world,
I implore the Demon King
to do so immediately.
Didn't you say you had matters to discuss?
What is it?
If the Demon King
has no intention of killing me,
then let's put aside our guards
and work together
for peace between our races.
I've heard that the Demon King
has feelings for my princess.
Is that true?
Yes.
You have great taste.
My Ning'an is wonderful.
However, in the past, I've had
many regrettable circumstances
and couldn't protect her properly.
It seems that Ning'an
will suffer less in the future.
As your father, I owe you an apology.
Since you were born,
I've rarely visited you.
First,
I feared that remembering your mother
would break my heart.
Second, everyone at court
had their eyes on you.
By staying away,
I was actually protecting you.
Come,
I'll take you to see your mother.
This is your mother.
Back then,
I was still a prince.
I first met your mother
at an academy.
She was standing in the corridor,
playing with a parrot,
teaching it to speak.
With just one glance,
I couldn't take my eyes off her.
After that,
I often went to the academy
to meet your mother.
As time went by,
we promised to grow old together.
I brought your mother
into my residence.
But I gradually discovered
your mother
not only talked to parrots,
but also frequently with cats and dogs,
and even with the fish in our home.
The servants
often saw these animals
communicating with your mother.
She often said
all things have spirits,
and that demons
are manifestations of natural power.
Until one day,
I saw with my own eyes
that your mother's blood
could attract animals from miles around.
It was then I had to accept the fact
that she was a demon.
A human prince's
love affair with a demon
was not accepted in this world.
For me to ascend the throne smoothly,
your mother
moved out of the palace
to live in a separate residence.
After giving birth to you,
she died from complications.
I didn't want to see
Ning'an living away from me,
but the entire court said
she was ill-fated
and must be killed.
I promised them
that when Ning'an came of age,
she would be married off
to a frontier kingdom.
Only then was I able to
keep her in the palace.
Now my daughter
has fallen in love with the Demon King,
it must be fate.
But I don't want the tragedy I experienced
to repeat itself with you two.
Therefore,
I hope you
can openly marry Ning'an.
Demon King,
are you willing?
Of course I am.
Good.
The Demon King
marrying a human princess means
the harmony between our races
will begin
with our royal families.
Isn't this better than
you trying so hard
to gradually heal the divide?
Father, you knew our plan?
It is also exactly what I have in mind.
However,
I have one more request.
I'd like to hear it.
I hope
you can find
the ancient Kunlun Mirror.